<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mohamed Fawas T</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Mohamed Fawas T</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:22:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohamedfawas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Favourite qoutes from the books I read</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/activity_logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:22:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/activity_logs/</guid><description>keeping empty for now</description></item><item><title>How to prepare for MSc data science/ data analytics entrance exams</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/msc_entrance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 20:45:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/msc_entrance/</guid><description>Nowadays there are many colleges providing data science courses. But to get admission to prestigious institutes you need to clear their entrance exam with a good rank. I myself was able to successfully clear the entrance test of IIITM-k (currently known as Digital University of Kerala). So, here I will explain some of the resources you can use to successfully clear the MSc data analytics/ data science entrance exams of DUK and CUSAT.</description></item><item><title>Free and quality resources to learn data science for a complete beginner</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/blog1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 07:54:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/blog1/</guid><description>Many free and paid resources are available online to learn data science-related topics. Here I will describe some of the freely available content in online which I myself had used and found good. So I will divide this learning plan into two levels. ie, level A and B.
Level A As a complete beginner, you should learn two things to improve your basics.
Basic statistics used in data science A programming language used in the data science domain Learning statistics For learning statistics concepts I would recommend the youtube playlist provided by Josh Starmer.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Bank assistant chatbot using RASA framework</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/projects/chatbot_project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 10:24:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/projects/chatbot_project/</guid><description>Created a Bank assistant chatbot using the RASA framework.
Click here to see the project report</description></item><item><title>Project Demand of Products at a Retail Outlet Based on Historical Data</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/projects/time_series_analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 10:26:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/projects/time_series_analysis/</guid><description>Developed a forecasting system with the help of ARIMA models and facebook&amp;rsquo;s prophet library. This forecasting system is used for predicting the demand for products at a retail outlet based on historical data.
Click here to see the project report</description></item><item><title>Research study and implementation of FastSK : Text classification Algorithm</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/projects/nlp_acad_proj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 10:25:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/projects/nlp_acad_proj/</guid><description>A study on FastSK Algorithm done as a part of mini-project during the second semester under the guidance of Dr.Asharaf and under the mentorship of Mr.Nikhil V Chandran
Click here to see the project report</description></item><item><title>About Mohamed Fawas</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 11:04:49 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/about/</guid><description>What I am doing now I have completed my post graduation in Computer Science with specialization in Data Analytics from Indian Institute of Information Technology and Management - Kerala, currently known as Digital University of Kerala .
I&amp;rsquo;m looking to collaborate on data engineering project.
My Background Work Experience full time AI/ML intern at Reflections Info Systems PVT LTD February 2022 to present part time AI/ML intern at Reflections Info Systems PVT LTD August 2021 to December 2021 Education MSc Computer Science with specialization in Data Analytics from Indian Institute of Information Technology and Management - Kerala (currently known as Digital University of Kerala), where I was advised by Dr.</description></item></channel></rss>