<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Mohamed Fawas T</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Mohamed Fawas T</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 16:22:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning computer vision</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/cv/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 16:22:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/cv/</guid><description>Currently I am a beginner in computer vision field. So here I will update some of the resources I would be using in this journey.
To clear basics I need to cover theoretical and basic topics of cv. For this I am using the lecture series by Shree Nayar of Columbia university.</description></item><item><title>Learning data structures and algorithms</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/dsa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 20:06:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/dsa/</guid><description>Here I will mention some of the resources from where you can learn about data structures and algorithms.
my code school DSA in python by Jovian Lead Coding by FRAZ</description></item><item><title>How to prepare for MSc data science/ data analytics entrance exams</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/msc_entrance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 20:45:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/msc_entrance/</guid><description>Nowadays there are many colleges providing data science courses. But to get admission to prestigious institutes you need to clear their entrance exam with a good rank. I myself was able to successfully clear the entrance test of IIITM-k (currently known as Digital University of Kerala). So, here I will explain some of the resources you can use to successfully clear the MSc data analytics/ data science entrance exams of DUK and CUSAT.</description></item><item><title>Free and quality resources to learn data science for a complete beginner</title><link>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/blog1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 07:54:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mohamedfawas.github.io/blogs/blog1/</guid><description>Many free and paid resources are available online to learn data science-related topics. Here I will describe some of the freely available content in online which I myself had used and found good. So I will divide this learning plan into two levels. ie, level A and B.
Level A As a complete beginner, you should learn two things to improve your basics.
Basic statistics used in data science A programming language used in the data science domain Learning statistics For learning statistics concepts I would recommend the youtube playlist provided by Josh Starmer.</description></item></channel></rss>